What's coming in older toilets 40 years old and older is lime will buildup in the jet way around the toilet.
When the water goes through the flush valve and comes out to the rim, these jets will get clogged with calcium.
I am not a proponent of cleaning them with a wire.
I am a proponent of using toilet bowl de-limer.
It?s an acid solution and what we do we take and we pour this whole quart in to the overflow tube all at once.
When it goes into the overflow tube, you will then notice the whole quart.
You will then notice that the acid is coming out of the rim of the toilet.
As it comes out, it is taking the lime in the jets with it.
Now most toilets, this will work fine, one quart will save them.
Occasionally I will need two quarts and rarely I'll need three.
But I'll tell you, for five dollars a quart, it?s much better to save an old toilet and de-lime the rim than it is to throw the toilet away.
We'll take this toilet and we're going to let it sit for 40 minutes and then we're going to flush it and we'll see how our results are and that should fix the toilet.